JOHNNATHAN BAXTER

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER



EDUCATION

FLATIRON SCHOOL Full Stack Web Development 06/2020 – 09/2020

RADFORD UNIVERSITY Bachelor of Science 08/2014 – 06/2019

TECHNICAL

SKILLS

FRONT-END JavaScript ES6 CSS/HTML Semantic

BACK-END REST/PostgreSQL MySQL/SQLite Node.js

FRAMEWORKS React / Redux Ruby on Rails

SOURCE CONTROL
Git (Git Flow)
GitHub

UI / UX Design Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe Acrobat Wireframing Webflow

INTERESTS

Typography Graphic Design Photography Athletics

PROFILE

Experienced JavaScript developer with a strong passion for React, paired with a high proficiency in Ruby on Rails. Adept at building web applications from the ground up both alone and on a team. Strong command of communication skills in optimizing solutions & effectively enhancing the performance of the overall team. Diligent problem-solver with an insatiable desire and motivation to learn.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

HOME SWEET HOME

GitHub | Demo

Home Sweet Home is a real estate platform that gives home buyers and sellers the opportunity to find and sell their homes independently. (JavaScript, Ruby, PostgreSQL)

- Incorporated Reactjs Context API framework to manage state between different components; including authenticated controlled forms for sign-up, log-in, posted listings and created offers.
- Utilized mapbox geocoder on front-end to geographically locate posted listings.
- Devised pagination for all listings, that goes through a 10-step process of filters and sorts.
- Integrated External API with RestClient to incorporate into house listing seed data.
- Constructed Rails backend API to manage database models that optimized application performance.

SERPIENTE

GitHub | Demo

Serpiente was built with a React front-end and a Rails back-end, with the intent of re-creating the famous snake arcade game with a little twist. (JavaScript, Ruby, PostgreSQL)

- Incorporated Reactjs context API to manage state between components to improve system design.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Engineered controlled forms for user log-in and sign-up
- Constructed Rails backend API to manage database models that optimized application performance.
- Debugged and troubleshooting (Browser Dev Tools / React Dev Tools)

BANKR

GitHub |

Bankr is an online banking platform that grants existing and new account holders the opportunity to initiate bank processes such as creating transfers, deposits, and withdrawals. (Ruby, SQLite)

- Initiated user authentication via Rails sessions and cookies, providing a secure web application for bank users.
- Developed custom routes to allow seamless user log-in & sign-up forms.
- Integrated self-referential database table allowing for correct designation of account roles and improving functionality.
- Implemented full CRUD functionality in controllers as well as multiple mathematical functions with models.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI/UX DESIGNER AND PROCESSION SYSTEMS
Procession Systems | 09/2019 - 01/2020

Prepared reports, researched and interfaced with involved management and parties to create and modify the GUI of the company's website. Developed wireframes with Adobe Suite to provide visual representation of user stories. Also conducted phone screens in support of involved clients; verified candidates' credentials qualifications, and availability.

INTERNSHIP

Radford Probation and Parole | 01/2019 - 06/2019

Work and maintain minor caseload to assist surrounding Probation Officer. Updated offender files within the agency's system of record. Also supported front-end receptionist operations and duties as assigned.